<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code on Statistics LatinAmerica</title>
    <link>/tags/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code on Statistics LatinAmerica</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Monte Carlo methods for estimation</title>
      <link>/post/2020-17-04-montecarlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-17-04-montecarlo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Two major classes of numerical problems that arise in data analysis procedures are optimization and integration problems. It is not always possible to analytically compute the estimators associated with a given model and we are often led to consider numerical solutions. One way to afford that problematic is to use simulation. Monte Carlo estimation refers to simulating hypothetical draws from a probability distribution, in order to calculate important quantities of that distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducción a R. ¿Cómo Empiezo?</title>
      <link>/post/2020-15-04-intro-a-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-15-04-intro-a-r/</guid>
      <description>Aprender un nuevo lenguaje de programación como R puede ser retador y en algunos casos hasta intimidante, pero existe una gran cantidad de material en la red que puede ser de gran utilidad, y existe una gran comunidad que igual a ti es entusiasta por aprender más y más de este lenguaje, así como expertos y profesores que están motivados a compartir un poco de sus conocimientos, solo debes aprender a buscar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>